Guide to the William Gifford Papers, approximately 1955-2015
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
William Gifford Papers
approximately 1955-2015
Gifford, William
1.0 cubic feet (1 box)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
The William Gifford Papers include correspondence between Gifford and former students and colleagues, including several poets and writers, such as Elizabeth Spires, Thomas Beller, Erica Funkhouser, and Curtis Sittenfeld.
Biographical Note
William Gifford (born 1928, Plainfield N.J.) taught in the English Department at Vassar from 1955-1996. A novelist and scholar of John Donne, Gifford taught Senior Composition and was a favorite among his students.
Chronology
1928 Gifford born in Plainfield, N.J.
1950 B.A. Swarthmore College
1952 M.A. University of California
1955 Ph.D. University of California
1955 Joined Vassar College Faculty, Department of English
1976 Appointed Full Professor, Vassar College Department of English
1996 Retired from Vassar College
Scope and Content Note
The William Gifford Papers include correspondence between Gifford and former students and colleagues, including several poets and writers, such as Elizabeth Spires, Thomas Beller, Erica Funkhouser, and Curtis Sittenfeld.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Names:
Spires, Elizabeth; Beller, Thomas; Funkhouser, Erica; Sittenfeld, Curtis
Subjects:
Teacher-student relationships; Novelists; College teachers
Organizations:
Vassar College--Faculty
VCL Categories
Literature and Writing; Vassar College
Encoding Information
Finding aid encoded by Jason Kovari, 20 Feb 2009.
Acquisition Information
Collection assembled and acquired through the efforts of William Gifford and The Archives and Special Collections Library, who petitioned materials from correspondents. The first accession was in 2003.
Correspondent List
- Amon, Eileen McDonald
- Beller, Thomas
- Blackorby, Melinda Clemmons
- Bussan, Mimi
- Callahan, Tara
- Davey, Eve Jenkins
- Elisofon, Marguerite Karter
- Engstrom, Katrena
- Franks, Lucinda
- Freund, Charles
- Funkhouser, Erika, 1993-2003; (2 Folders)
- Jacabs, Sherry
- Katri, Cindy Lenorowitz
- Kennison, Cynthia, 1975-1994; (2 Folders)
- Kilgore, Kathryn, 1970-2003; (2 Folders)
- Kinnison, Karen
- Kosek, Raphael
- Li, Mei Sun
- Lobl, Rebecca
- McAlden, Susan Rosenberg
- Moldow, Erika
- Newell, Bonnie
- Nurnberger, Alissa
- Passer, Richard
- Pearson, Amy Hethcoat
- Price, Roberta
- Reynolds, Nancy
- Schoenbrod, Kathryn
- Scranton, Risa Scherer
- Sheffield, Anne
- Silverman, Taije
- Sinder-Brown, Vivian
- Sittenfeld, Curtis
- Socolow, Elizabeth Anne Sussman
- Spiller, Jill
- Spires, Elizabeth, 1974-2008; (12 Folders)
  — Includes poems written by Spires at Vassar, annotated by William Gifford
- Sutton-Mattocks, Alison, 1976-2003; (3 Folders)
- Vag, Anna-Maria
- Wallach, Jeffrey
- Warden, Sarah
- Zimmerman, Miriam